BINAN BOOKSTORE, USED BOOK TRADE
(滨南书店 二手书交易)
HONMARU FIREWORKS FESTIVAL
(鸿丸 烟火节)
Sajo.
佐城同学
What's up?
怎么了吗
It feels like it's going to rain.
好像快要下雨了
Really?
真的假的
Indeed, it's overcast.
的确是乌云密布啊
It's starting to rain.
下雨了
Ichinose,
一之濑同学
can you help bring in the cart from outside?
你可以帮忙把外面的推车收起来吗
O-Okay.
好的
Na-Natsukawa?
夏川...
Um…
那个…
You better come in.
你快进来吧
Natsukawa.
夏川同学
Here you go.
这个给你
Thank you, Ichinose.
谢谢你 一之濑同学
No problem.
不客气
She seems like a completely different person, no?
她给人的感觉不太一样了耶
Indeed.
嗯 的确
At first, I thought she was very humble.
她人看起来老老实实的
But she's actually a very smart person.
但她其实很机灵
What brings you here today?
你今天怎么会来这里呢
I just wanted to check in and see how you're doing.
我一时兴起想说来看看你打工
You could have come on a day with better weather.
那你也不用挑这种天气来吧
Otherwise, the distance between you two will only get further.
要不然你们的距离又会越来越远
Will you continue working here?
你之后还会继续打工吗
No, I'm going to quit soon.
没有 我很快就会离职了
I'll resign when the summer vacation ends.
暑假结束后我就不做了
Because that was my plan from the beginning.
我原本的计划就是这样
Oh, I see.
原来如此…
Is that okay?
这样好吗
What do you mean?
你是指什么事
You know…
就是...
Ichinose can handle things on her own now.
一之濑同学已经能独当一面了
It will be okay even if I'm not here.
就算我不在也没问题的
Hi.
大家好
It's about to pour down.
没想到快到步之前下起雨来...
It's Senior Natsukawa.
是夏川学姐耶
Hi. You're all wet.
你好...你的衣服都湿了
I wasn't expecting to see you here.
没想到我会在这遇到学姐
Thank you for guiding the campus tour back then.
谢谢学姐你之前当我们的向导
You better dry your clothes first.
你还是先把衣服擦干吧
Even though I just used this towel.
虽然这是我刚才用过的毛巾...
Fuka?
小风香...
Senior Mina, today I…
深那学姐 今天我...
-Over here, come here. -What's up?
-你快过来这边 -怎么了吗
I'll take care of the shop. Go ahead and talk.
店就交给我来顾吧
That scared me.
吓了我一跳
You mean Miss Sasaki?
你说笹木小姐吗
She and Ichinose get along great.
她跟一之濑同学感情很好
She frequently visits Ichinose in order to discuss their shared reading experiences.
她常来找一之濑同学交换读书心得
Frequently?
她常来...
You seem to get along great with them.
你跟她们还真是亲近啊
Don't you have to follow them?
你不用过去找她们吗
How could I leave you here alone?
我怎么能丢下你一个人在这
Natsukawa?
夏川
What's wrong?
你怎么了
N-Nothing.
我...没事
You don't look fine.
你看起来不像没事啊
I've said it's nothing.
我都说没事了
Why are you so careless?
你太不小心了吧...
Oh, sorry!
啊 不好意思
We weren't sneaking a peek or trying to eavesdrop.
我们绝对没有想偷听或偷看
Sorry!
抱歉打扰了
I had previously invited you
我之前说过...
to my home. Right?
要邀请你来我家的事
Yeah.
嗯 我还记得
But did you come all this way just to say that?
但你专程过来就是为了这件事吗
That's due to… I just happened to be nearby.
我...只是刚好来到这附近
But you just said you wanted to check in?
但你刚才明明说一时兴起想来看看
Do you need to care about these details?
你有必要在意这些细节吗
Sorry.
对不起
I'm just that kind of detail-oriented person.
我就是会拘泥于细节的性格
But does the invitation
不过 去你家的约定
to your home still count?
那还算数吗
How come it doesn't count?
为什么不算数
NIGHT IS SHORT, GO LOVE, GIRL Because you mentioned many precautions…
(《春宵苦短 恋爱吧少女》) 毕竟你说了很多注意事项
I thought it certainly wouldn't count.
我还以为就告吹了
That's because…
那是因为...
-AS YOU WISH! -GEEZ
(-悉听尊便！) (-真是的) 那是因为...
Because I hope you can be a good brother to Airi.
我希望你能当爱莉的好哥哥
Broth--
当她哥哥...
No,
不是啦
that's not what I mean.
我不是那个意思
Alright, just calm down.
我知道啦 你冷静点
Anyway, I sincerely hope you can come.
总之我是真心希望你能来
I'm also looking forward to the day you visit…
我也很期待你来...
(Dreaming Boy is a Realist, The)
《满怀美梦的少年是现实主义者》
(Because You Are My Refuge)
(因为你是我的容身之处啊)
The time has come.
是时候了
What are you up to, Sajo?
小佐城你在干嘛啊
Apparel make the woman?
这就是所谓的人靠衣装吗
Zero points.
零分
Aren't I complimenting you?
我是在夸奖你耶
Wow, I'm so happy.
哦 我好开心啊
Wait a minute.
你等等啊
I'm not mentally prepared yet.
我还没做好心理准备耶
Coming.
来了
Negative one hundred million points.
扣你一亿分
At least say something.
你至少说句话吧
Come on in.
你们进来吧
It's Sister Kei and…
是圭姐姐跟...
Who are you?
你是谁
Hello.
你好 初次见面
My name is Sajo Wataru.
本人名叫佐城涉
Nice to meet you.
请多指教
You can skip the formalities.
这么拘谨的招呼就免了吧
Airi,
小爱莉
he is Wataru.
这个人是阿涉
Wataru. Do you know how to say it?
他叫阿涉 你会念吗
Wataru?
阿涩...
You're so cute!
你真是太可爱了
Is it easier for you to call him Sajo?
叫他佐城是不是会比较简单呢
Sajo?
佐城...
Sajo!
佐城！
Charge, Sajo!
冲啊 佐城
Move forward!
向前冲
Yes, sir!
遵命
I should have known better than
我太小看五岁小孩了
to discount a five-year-old's enthusiasm.
精力太旺盛了吧
Faster, faster!
再快点
You're too slow, Sajo!
佐城你太慢了
Are you okay?
你还好吗
I'm fine…
我...我没事
I want to ride a horse.
我要骑马马
Airi, don't be so willful.
爱莉你别这么任性
Does Airi usually
爱莉她平时
play such difficult games?
都玩这么高难度的游戏吗
She usually just reads picture books
她平常就是看看绘本
or plays house.
或是玩过家家
That's nice.
真好啊
Airi seems to like you very much.
小爱莉她很喜欢你呢
Huh? Really?
咦 是吗
Look.
你看吧
She usually doesn't jump on people like this.
她平常不会这样扑到别人身上的
Sajo is the second child in his family, right?
小佐城在他家排行老二对吧
There must be something they have in common.
他跟小爱莉一定有什么共同点
Airi is still overly attached to him.
话虽如此 爱莉也太粘他了
You little rascal, watch my comeback!
你这个小鬼头 看我的逆袭
Take this!
看招
I've never seen Airi so outgoing before.
我还是第一次看到 小爱莉这么不怕生呢
Is this the power of Sajo?
这就是小佐城的威力吗
Oh my.
哎呀
I had such a great time.
我玩得好尽兴啊
Seeing you tired like that is so funny.
看你累成这样 笑死我了
You're taking her playtime too seriously.
你也太认真陪她玩了
Wasn't it you who said
还不是夏川你说的
you hoped I'd be a good brother to her?
你希望我当个好哥哥
Wait, don't say that here!
等等 你别说出来啊
Brother?
哥哥？
What? What are you talking about?
什么啊 你们在说什么
When I decided to pay a visit to Natsukawa's home…
就是我们决定来夏川家的时候...
D-Don't talk about that anymore.
那件事就别再提了
Huh? I'm so curious.
我好好奇哦
Curious!
好奇好奇
Kei! And Airi too!
圭  爱莉你也是
Wow, your big sister is angry.
哇 你姐姐生气了
Airi, come here.
小爱莉你快来我这
So cute, so cute.
你真是有够可爱
Aika, did you go through a phase like hers?
小爱你小时候也有这段时期吧
In other words,
也就是说
Airi represents Natsukawa as a child.
爱莉就是小时候的夏川
Don't think so strangely, okay?
你的见解也太奇怪了吧
Am I like my sister?
我跟姐姐一样吗
Yes.
没错哦
The energetic Natsukawa… Hmm…
精力旺盛活蹦乱跳的夏川...
You're not thinking of anything strange, are you?
你不会又在想什么奇怪的事吧
No, nothing is on my mind.
没啊 我没有在想什么
You're too agitated.
你慌张什么啊
What do you mean, Kei?
圭你干嘛啦
Nothing.
没什么啊
Airi, let me ask you.
小爱莉我问你
Do you want a big brother?
你想不想要一个哥哥
A big brother who plays with you every day.
他可以每天陪你玩
I want! Big brother!
我想要哥哥
What are you saying?
你在说什么啊
Big brother…
什么哥哥...
Huh?
哎呀呀
But I'm talking about a male
我只是在说
who is slightly older than she is?
年纪稍长的年轻男生 怎么了吗
Stop it. Kei, you are so naughty.
讨厌 圭你真是的
Sajo, have you rested well?
佐城你休息完了吗
I've rested.
嗯 我休息完了
Then come and play with me.
那我们来玩吧
I have burned out and turned into white ash.
我已燃烧殆尽 化作雪白的灰
Aika's mom is back.
小爱的妈妈来了
What are you doing?
你在干嘛啊
What are you acting cool for?
装什么酷啊你
Welcome home, Mom.
妈 你回来了啊
I'm back.
我回来了
Do we have guests?
有客人吗
-They are Kei and… -Hello, nice to meet you.
-这是圭跟.. -您好 幸会
What are you doing?
你干嘛啦
You are Sajo, right?
你就是佐城同学对吧
I have heard about you from Aika.
我有听爱华说过你的事
About me?
我的事是指？
Let me think.
我想想哦...
E-Enough, they're going to leave.
好...够了 他们要回家了啦
What a pity,
真可惜
I wanted to have a long talk with Sajo.
我还想跟佐城同学多聊聊呢
Sajo!
佐城
Um…
呃 那个…
Mom!
妈妈
Y-You can chat next time, right?
下次再聊就好了吧
That's great, Sajo.
太好了呢 小佐城
It appears that there will be a next time. Next time.
似乎还有下次呢
I'll send them off.
我送他们出去
Alright.
好好好
Sajo, come to play again next time.
佐城同学 下次要再来玩哦
Airi, be gentler to me next time.
小爱莉 下次你要对我温柔点哦
See you next time, Airi.
小爱莉 下次见
See you next time!
再见
Airi has grown up.
小爱莉越长越大了呢
Has she?
有吗
I see her every day, so I don't feel anything.
我每天看着她所以没什么感觉
She might grow taller than you soon.
她说不定很快就会长得比你高了
I-I'm still growing too.
我现在也还在长高啊
By the way, Airi looks a lot like her mom.
话说小爱莉长得跟妈妈很像呢
Now that you mention it, indeed.
好像是哦
To say it, Aika probably looks more like her dad?
硬要说的话 小爱应该长得比较像爸爸
A beautiful mom and beautiful sister?
是美女妈妈跟美女姐妹呢
Don't say it in such a strange way.
你别用这么奇怪的说法好不好
Is this a strange way of putting it?
我的说法很奇怪吗
Is that so?
这样啊...
By the way, Natsukawa,
话说 夏川
what have you said about me?
你都说了我什么啊
Your mother said she heard about me from you, didn't she?
你妈妈不是说她有听你提过我吗
I didn't say anything specific.
我也没说什么特别的事啦
My house is over here. Bye.
我家往这边 那就再见咯
That fellow…
这家伙...
You've walked me far enough.
你送我到这就好了
Thank you, Natsukawa.
谢谢你
Let me walk you a bit more.
我再送你走一段路吧
Once in a while, anyway.
反正难得一次
Huh? Wait.
啊 等等...
(Dreaming Boy is a Realist, The)
《满怀美梦的少年是现实主义者》
Recently, I've been enjoying school life.
我最近觉得校园生活很开心
School life?
校园生活？
Now I can chat with other students,
现在我会跟其他同学聊东聊西
and go out with them.
也会跟大家出去玩
It makes me say, "This is school life!"
让我发现原来这就是所谓的校园生活
But all this is not a matter of course.
但这一切并非天经地义
Because this was not the case when I was in junior high.
毕竟我国中的时候就不是这么回事
Sorry.
抱歉...
It must be all my fault, right?
那都是我害的吧
Not at all.
才不是呢
That's not what I meant.
我想说的不是这个
Even if you hadn't been there,
那时候就算阿涉你不在
I wouldn't have had the energy
我一定也没有多余的心力
to enjoy school life
去享受校园生活
or talk with classmates at the time.
或是跟同学聊天
Because I could only concentrate on studying at the time.
因为当时我完全无暇他顾
Are you still awake? You should sleep early.
你还没睡啊 早点休息吧
I woke up.
我中途醒来了
Mom,
妈妈
I plan to apply for Koetsu High School.
我想要考鸿越高中
They have a tuition waiver policy, right?
他们有学费减免制度对吧
What are you talking about? You don't need to worry about--
这种事用不着你操心...
And their uniform looks nice.
而且他们的制服也很好看
I see.
原来如此...
But I still feel sorry for you.
但我还是觉得对不起你
I must be a nuisance, right?
我一定很碍事吧
Yes.
是啊
But if I could see myself from that time,
但是 如果让当时的我来看
I might find it unbelievable to see my current self.
我可能会对现在的自己 感到有点难以置信
How is it that I can be so happy now?
为什么我能过得这么开心呢...
I think, the turning point was probably…
我想原因大概就是...
He hasn't been bothering you lately.
他最近不会来纠缠你了呢
That's great, Natsukawa.
真是太好了
I was a bit worried.
我还有点担心你呢
Everyone knew about my existence.
大家都知道了我的存在
If it wasn't for this,
要不是这样的话
I think I would be just like in junior high school.
我想我一定又跟国中时一样
That…
那是...
Sort of my missionary work.
算是我的传教活动吧
But I'm still sorry.
但还是很抱歉
Don't apologize to me, Wataru.
阿涉 我就叫你不要跟我道歉了
I'm capricious.
我也有任性的地方
No, you didn't.
你哪里任性了
Even if I have a pleasant chat with Kei and everyone else,
就算我跟圭还有大家聊得很愉快
I always feel unsatisfied.
我仍会觉得少了些什么
That's true.
那的确...
Maybe it's a little capricious.
是有点任性没错呢
It seems like there's always one person missing
每当我有这种感受时
whenever that feeling comes over me.
总有某个人不在场
And that person is always a little further away from me.
而某人又总是会跟我保持一点距离
That's because…
那是因为...
If I joined, I might be in your way.
我要是加入了 大概会妨碍到你
Not at all.
才没有这回事
Because…
因为...
you are my refuge.
你是我的容身之处啊
Natsukawa.
夏川...
By the way, today…
对哦 今天...
There's a fireworks festival.
有烟火节
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I'm afraid of loud noises.
我怕很吵的声响
Na-Natsukawa?
夏...夏川
You don't want to call my first name anymore?
你已经不愿意叫我的名字了吗
F-Forget I said that.
你...当我没说
B-But…
可是...
You should come and talk to me like before.
你要像之前一样来找我聊天啊
If you aren't there,
你要是不在的话
my life will be out of sync.
我的生活都不对劲了
Aika looks more childish than usual today.
爱华今天看起来比平时更稚嫩
Because I was worried about her, even though
因为我实在放不下她
Aika was the one who walked me home at first, I eventually walked her home.
明明一开始是她送我 最后却变成了我送她回家
But this might just be my excuse.
不过这应该只是我的借口
I'll leave then.
那我走了
Thank you, Wataru.
谢谢你 阿涉
See you next time, Aika.
下次见 爱华
You really picked a bad time to bother me.
你就专挑这种时候来烦我
What does it matter?
有什么关系
You're getting used to the school work anyway.
反正你也快熟悉学校的工作了
You'll also be helping out with the upcoming cultural festival.
接下来的校庆也劳烦你帮忙了
I don't want to.
我不要
Alright!
好啦 我知道了
Stop inexplicably grabbing my shoulders and wrists.
你别莫名其妙抓住我的肩膀跟手腕
It's terrifying.
有够恐怖
That violent girl.
那个暴力女
She's completely taken advantage of me.
她完全食髓知味了
I am not a handyman.
我才不是工具人好吗
Good morning, Wataru.
早安 阿涉
Good morning, Natsukawa.
早啊 夏川
Huh? What's the matter?
怎么了吗
Your tie is crooked.
你领带歪了
It's the start of a new term. You need to be serious!
新学期开始了 你认真一点好吗
O-Okay.
哦 好的
And your hair too…
还有你的头发...
Don't bother with my hair.
头发我自己来
Look, it's okay now.
这样行了吧
Let's go.
我们走吧
Did you get a haircut?
你剪头发了吗
No.
没有啊
I-Is that so?
哦 是吗
Geez.
真是的...
Dreams are beautiful, reality is harsh.
梦想很美好 现实很虚无
From the moment that soccer ball flew in front of my eyes,
从那颗足球飞到我面前的那刻起
my view became gray.
我眼前的景色就变成了一片灰色
But unknowingly, it became colorful again.
但不知不觉间又变得多彩多姿
This may not be a coincidence.
这或许并非偶然
Because recognizing reality, living each day seriously,
因为认清现实 认真度日
is the answer to getting closer
就是让我朝着自己的梦想
STUDENT UNION OFFICE to my dreams.
(学生会办公室) 更近一步的答案
My name is Sajo Wataru.
我的名字是佐城涉
I am a common high school boy being tossed around
我是一个被梦想和现实拉扯 没有余力向前看
by dreams and reality, without any energy to move forward.
平凡无奇的一名男高中生
(Dreaming Boy is a Realist, The)
《满怀美梦的少年是现实主义者》
My life
我的生活
will probably continue like this.
一定会一直这样继续下去吧